we couldn't hear the timer very well in
this game and so our timing is a little
bit all over the place but this is a
supposedly anyway 10-minute two-player
game one minute per turn game on gender
enjoy
what a naughty issue we have with gender
it's it's it's such a huge question of
dualities non-duality x' what are we
actually dealing with when we say J
[Music]
there's two issues here as well three
issues I guess there's the biological
reproductive notion of gender right
sexual the necessary necessity for sex
is to create variation this is one thing
then there is the cultural construct of
gender assigning characteristics and
roles to people based if not entirely
then largely on their gender and falling
into raising boys and girls in certain
ways so there's that but then umbrella
in both of those is the the eternal
energy of the masculine and the feminine
right that the first division if you
were one of the first divisions of you
like have equated in to the masculine
and the feminine it's interesting we
assign all sorts of genders especially
not in English languages like French and
Italian or German or wacking gender into
all sorts of things and and it's quite
difficult really to unravel what's
really going on when we say the Divine
Feminine or the masculine and start to
assign these things to different genders
for us in fact when we look at gender in
humanity those divisions don't really
seem to well perhaps they they apply
some more stereotypically but they're so
often broken within the stereotype one
wonders how
how how useful it is really to have
those individual divisions according to
agenda yeah it's the it's the conflation
of the masculine and the feminine with
the man and the woman it's a failure to
recognize that the masculine and a
feminine reside in both men and women
right and that the biological necessity
for having men and women necessitates
certain physical differences right and
so there are stereotypical physical
differences women have more fat in their
bodies women are generally shorter
weaker and so on of course you can
always find examples of peak tall strong
women and short weak men of course that
is that if that is the case but broadly
speaking and so part of the gender
assignation that has gone on it is
surely due to this biological thing
because men are stronger they do more
physical labor for example some
interesting things especially when you
go to something like the yin and the
yang and they talk about the feminine
and the masculine where where the
masculine perhaps represents order and
light and force and the feminine action
represent chaos and negative things so
it's extremely this extremely
interesting thing perhaps it's
unfortunate perhaps is unfortunate the
feminine the masculine are seen as
separate rather than opposite ends of a
scale in which we we enjoy all sorts of
overlapping overlapping ways of being
rather than saying masculine is like
family
as with any duality it is what it is the
duality is the duality that duality is
is is one of the ways subjects an object
up and down black and white hot and cold
light and dark these things are simply
polarities that we use to make sense of
the world the difficulties arise when
you start assigning virtuous or evil
whatever characteristics to these things
and traditionally the dark is bad and
the light is good and so the the yin and
the yang this is an inter penetrating
thing right the symbol of the dowser is
is a symbol of inter penetration and so
the masculine energy if you like is the
one which pushes in the feminine energy
is one which yields and envelops and
there is you know there is no yielding
and enveloping without something pushing
against you there's nothing there is no
pushing without something to yield an
envelop these the date they are one and
the same thing separated only in our
minds and the ways that and and the ways
that we act and we see them and assign
values to them the yin and yang is a
very ancient thing but it doesn't mean
it's right it's not it's not necessarily
correct it's not necessarily right to
divide things or to imagine that we have
polarities and everything it's not
necessarily a good idea to
put things into polarities and to feel
that gender actually exists in that
manner for example we can we can
consider that that we're looking at
perhaps a circle of being rather than
[Music]
perhaps it as a swirling sense of being
we have masculine type of things of
feminine type of things instead we just
go round and round and round within
something like that's even more text
being gender even considers something
that may not even be even be a permanent
state of being human beings are fluid
that fluid and what they feel they fluid
and what they think they are so as a
social construct rather than the
biological one it's a social construct
gender may be something that is
definitely not a priority but a fluid
changing flowing thing you unit see
seems to be the thing that we're sort of
dancing around here that the the the the
separation into the masculine and
feminine is absolutely a construct right
it is it is a mental construct of human
beings in in that way it sits
it's an item unity is amorphous unity
doesn't have any bound reason any
membranes around it there is no subjects
and object there's no relationship and
so that the polarizing the separating
into dualities is is is necessary for
existence as we understand it living as
we understand it awareness as we
understand it it's not real but it's
circularity asperities as he is a useful
construct but it's not necessarily
always a good map for what is let's
consider a female as being the whole and
a male being a specialist part of a
female as we call that the female is the
basic pattern of human kind
so rather than one end or the other we
have one that is the whole another that
is part of the whole perhaps we can turn
around things we can break out from our
thinking in polarities and open our mind
to more subtle or more fluid ways of
considering who we are and where we how
we relate to each other